# <POL PIELLA ABADIA>

- hi@polpiella.dev
- +44 7759769444
- https://polpiella.dev
- github.com/pol-piella
- /in/pol-piella-81b846115/

Passionate senior software engineer with over 5 years of experience in building scalable mobile applications. Eager to join a company to make an impact and help develop beautiful user experiences while maintaining a fully tested and well architected codebase. I am always trying to learn and give back to the community through technical articles and public speaking at international conferences.

# MOST RECENT WORK EXPERIENCE

# **iOS Software Engineer (promoted to Senior)**

**BBC** iPlayer

September 2021 - Present

### Responsibilities

- Play an important role in the architecting and decision making of new features.
- Mentor other members of the team and help onboarding new starters.
- Facilitator of a cross-product iOS team looking for opportunities to use SwiftUI within our products.

# **Key Achievements**

- Significantly modernising the CI and build tooling in the product space.
- Successfully rewriting legacy features into new modules using modern iOS technologies.
- Helping shape up the architecture of key parts of the application.
- Introducing a first SwiftUI component in the application and making use of SwiftUI previews to speed up development and feedback.
- Introducing and successfully pitching the idea of a Home Screen widget to stakeholders, making it into a prioritised piece of work.
- Working successfully with designers in a major UI refresh of the application.

# PREVIOUS WORK EXPERIENCE

# iOS Software Engineer

Student Beans April 2020 - September 2021

### iOS Junior Software Engineer

Music Tribe August 2018 - April 2020

### **EDUCATION**

# Master of Electronic Engineering with Music Techology Systems

University of York York, United Kingdom 2014 - 2018

# **SKILLS & PROFICIENCIES**

- Swift, SwiftUI and UIKit
- Mentoring
- Public Speaking
  - I have spoken at a number of events and conferences. In 2022 I will be speaking at Do iOS in Amsterdam and the Mobile Devops Summit by Bitrise.
- Technical Writing Articles I have a blog where I post regularly.

# LANGUAGES

- Spanish (Native)
- Catalan (Native)
- English (Fluent)